utah.edu 2019-06-06

# Privacy Statement - The University of Utah

The University of Utah has created this statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. This document explains how we gather, use, and protect your information. 

## We Don't Sell Your Contact Information

While using this site, you may choose to submit personal information through email or online forms. We will use this information to process your requests. But we will not intentionally sell, share, or distribute your personal information to third parties, except as required by law or university policy. 

## **EU General Data Protection Regulation**

Please be aware of the University’s GDPR Privacy Notice that supplements this Privacy Statement. The GDPR Privacy Notice applies generally to the provision of personal information by individuals in the European Economic Area. The GDPR Privacy Notice explains how we meet our obligations under the European Union General Data Protection Regulation with respect to such information. The GDPR Privacy Notice can be found at https://www.utah.edu/privacy/gdpr.php. 

## Statistical Logs Kept

The University uses reporting programs to collect data about visitor traffic to our site. We do not attempt to personally identify visitors. Instead we collect data to analyze in aggregate to determine trends and improve our sites. Here are some examples of the types of data we routinely collect: 

  * Internet address of computer
  * Browser type
  * Referring web page
  * Date, time & duration of visit

## Cookies Used to Preserve Data

Some U sites require the use of cookies (bits of data passed by your browser to our site). For instance, the My.Utah.edu portal uses cookies (active only during your session) to remember password and menu settings. You are not required to use My.Utah.edu; this tool is provided for your convenience. If you prefer not to receive cookies, you can turn them off in your browser or set your browser to ask you before accepting new cookies. 

## Security Programs Running

We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, to assist in maintaining data security, and to assist in correctly using the information we collect online. We do not intentionally release personal information gleaned from these programs to others, except as required by law. 

## Security Precautions You Should Take

Although we make every effort to secure our networks, the University cannot guarantee privacy of online communications. Use discretion in providing information in online classes, chatrooms, or other open forums on the Web. If you use My.Utah.edu to access personal records, be sure to "lock up" when you leave by exiting the site AND closing your browser. Otherwise, the next person to use the computer may see your information. 

## Alternate Ways to Submit Information

You have a choice about whether to provide personal information online. For other options, contact the site manager and learn how you can provide information by phone, mail, fax or in person. 

## Other Sites Have Different Policies

This site contains links to other independently managed U sites. Some may use information for purposes other than stated above; be sure to read their separate privacy statements. U sites also contain links to sites outside the university; these sites may have their own privacy statement--or none at all. We urge you to exercise caution when providing personal data to any site. Check their policies and contact them if you have questions. 

## Protecting Children's Privacy

We encourage parents to explore our website with their children. If we learn that a child under age 13 has provided personally identifiable information to our sites, we will promptly remove this from our files. For more on children's privacy rights, read about the [Children's Online Privacy Protection Act](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/privacyinitiatives/childrens.html) at the FTC's website. 

## Changing Your Information

Here's how to review or change your personal profile information (address, home phone, e-mail): 

  * **On the Web** – Log in to the [Campus Information Services](http://cis.utah.edu/) and click your address, phone, or email to edit. 
  * **In Person** – Visit Registration Service Window #13 on the 2nd floor of the [Student Services Building.](http://www.map.utah.edu/index.html?code=ssb)
  * **By Phone** – Call the Registration Division (801) 581-8969. 

## Related Policies

  * [Policies & Procedures 1-12 U Institutional Data Management Policy](https://regulations.utah.edu/it/4-001.php)

## Health Information Privacy

The University, and those who work, teach, and learn here, value the privacy of the health information you provide us. The [Information Security and Privacy Office](http://privacy.utah.edu/) website explains how we handle the personal information that you share with us as a patient, health/benefits plan member, or participant in a research study. The website also provides information explaining the rights you have regarding that information and how to exercise those rights. We provide the notices to make you aware of these practices and to comply with the law, including the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) of 1996. 

University policies are subject to change. We encourage you to check back for updates from time to time. If you have additional questions about this privacy statement, we invite you to contact: 

University Webmaster  
101 South Wasatch Drive #215  
Salt Lake City, UT 84112  
(801) 585-7320  

**Last Updated** : 6/4/18 

**Effective Date:** 10/24/03
